你好,他好,大家好
hello hello everyone
进来,坐好,我要开始讲了.下午好
come sit stay awhile good afternoon
今天大家过的如何?噢,大家的答案我喜欢听
how's everyone today the that's what I
like to hear
我叫大卫-史密斯,我是NewCircle培训中心的Android老大
I hello everyone my name is Dave Smith I
am the Android lead for new circle
我叫大卫-史密斯,我是NewCircle培训中心的Android老大
training
我们对很多技术做开源的培训,Android只是其中一项
we do open Source Training a number of
technologies and reduce happens to be
我们对很多技术做开源的培训,Android只是其中一项
one of them
不过言归正传,今天我要谈的主题是
I'm gonna be here to you today to talk
about
精通RecyclerView的布局.
我们的关注点不在于如何具体的
mastering recycler view layouts I we're
not gonna talk more specifically about
具体的使用RecyclerView
how to use recycler view
而在于如何
in the generals a sense today we're going
to be talking mostly about building
自定义RecyclerView的布局管理器
custom layout managers with recyclerView
以及我们在自定义布局管理器过程中
应该注意的事情
and how we can kind of get through that
process so
先给大家说说我站在这儿的原因
a little bit about why I'm here standing
in front of you today
正所谓前人栽树,后人乘凉嘛
call it a bit of (Hannah) a humanitarian
effort
我会给你介绍你可能需要到的工具(指API的帮助类)
I'm really here to give you the tools
hopefully that you will need
当你尝试使用RecyclerView时,当你为了特定的需求
if you are trying to use recycler view
you're trying to customize it for your
而去自定义RecyclerView时将有所帮助
specific purposes
我会尽力带你把这整个过程走通
and trying to get you through that
process with out losing
来让你少走弯路
you know essentially losing your mind
I'm so
在我们深入讲解之前,我想确保大家是不是都在一个级别上
before we dive too deep into the details
I just wanna make sure that everybody's
在我们深入讲解之前,我想确保大家是不是都在一个级别上
on the same page so
那么大家所看到的这种情况是从哪儿来的呢
where does this all this come from you
know the
众所周知,视图回收的这种主意是一种惯用的技术,
this idea of view recycling is a
pattern that's used in mobile all over
其被用于所有的移动平台
the place all mobile platforms do this
android恰好是其中一个而已.
android just happens to do it as well
it has done this
从android1.0就有了,说具体点,这种机制体现在
since version 1 I  most specifically
LisView这个控件上.想必各位都用过不下百十次吧
in the format ListView most of us have
probably use a number of times
我只是好奇,请举下手.各位都有谁真的尝试着
I am just curious shorthand how many
have you have actually tried to use
去用RecyclerView呢
recycler view
还不错嘛.那么,有谁试着去写自定义的布局管理器呢
before,pretty good.how many have you tried to
build your own layout manager
貌似人不多咯.不过超过我的预期咯
okay more than I expected good
其实更重要的是,各位的头发都还在.这比啥都好啊.
and mostly you still have your hair
that even better so
这种对视图的回收利用机制使我们
this this idea view recycling is really
it allows developers and it allows
的设备能够
devices to
展现非常大的数据集合,可能是成百上千条
present large collections of data
maybe hundreds or even thousands of
的数据项
items
给用户.但又仅仅用有限的几个视图便可完成
to the user but only using a handful of
views
不必创建跟数据项个数一样多的视图来展示数据
not creating as many views as we need to
display that data
作为替代,使用一种叫做 回收->绑定 的过程
but instead, using a process called
recycling of rebinding
来将用户需要看到的数据绑定到各个视图之上
of data to individual views as the
user needs to see them
可以这么讲,
so basically like we've got going here
we have this idea that
显示用户数据集的视图的个数
the number reviews necessary to show the
user their collection
只等于我们屏幕上能显示出的视图的个数
is only what we need to be able to show
on screen
一旦用户开始跟他的数据集交互,不管是上划
and as the user is interacting with this
content whether there's scrolling up
还是怎么划
around
只要视图被划出屏幕,这个视图就不需要了.但是
as view scroll off-screen they're no
longer necessary but rather than
对于将要到来的新的数据,不采用创建一个新视图的方式
creating new views for the new data
coming in
而是把这个旧的视图重新填充数据
we can simply take the old views
repurpose them with new data
平移其到一个新位置,然后让它划入屏幕即可
shift them to a new location and allow
them to slide back n
因此,用这种办法,才使得我们能够展示成百上千的数据项
so that way we can display hundreds of
thousands of items
仅仅使用有限的几个视图.大体上,
with only a handful of views. generally
you're gonna see you
你会发现RecyclerView和ListView需要创建的视图个数
recycler views or list views creating as
many viewers as necessary to display on
会比展示在屏幕上的视图的个数多一两个
screen plus maybe one or two more
这跟采用的算法有关.
depending on how the algorithm works
okay
再重申一次,我不会讲太多如何使用RecyclerView
so again I'm not gonna talk too much
about how to use recycler view I think
这方面有很好的文档
there's some good documentation on that
but
RecyclerView的精华在于
the basics have recycler view is that
recycler view is a
RecyclerView是对这种机制的革新,更加灵活易用
more flexible,evolution of this
pattern
其允许我们来对可复用的集合创建
that allows us to create these
recyclable collections in
各种自定义(布局,动画,装饰)的实现.之前,我们只有ListView
all kinds of custom implementations you
know previously we only had list view
是一个可在垂直方向上滚动的列表
which was a vertical scrolling list
开发者们已经为其做过一些自定制的实现了
there have been some custom
implementations done by other developers
比方说水平滚动的列表.等等其他定制的效果
ways to do this maybe horizontally
or another custom ways
RecyclerView为之前大家所需要的实现提供了一个框架
recyclerView bring that all together
into a framework so because it that
因此,要想使用RecyclerView
recycler you cannot be used
你必须要提供一个布局管理器不可.这俩必须成对使用,不然
without a layout manager.the two always
have to pair together in fact if you try
当你尝试实例化一个没有定义布局管理器的RecyclerView时
to instantiate a RecyclerView without
a layup manager
你会得到一个没有用的异常,会让你的程序崩溃
you'll get a very unhelpful exception about
that will crash your application
所以,用RecyclerView之前,咱一定要有布局管理器
OK.so you always need to set a layout
manager before you try to use a recycler
view
为了使你能登堂入室,或者说为了便于应对最常用的场合
and to sort of get you started or cover
most use cases
框架在这方面干的很不错.为我们提供了
the framework has done a pretty good job
of providing
几个自带的布局管理器.在大多数情况下,你甚至有可能
a handful of its own layout managers that
in a lot cases you might even be able
都用得上
to use wholesale
如果你从Lpreview或者从RecyclerView最初版本发布以来
and if you haven't looked at recycler
view since the L reviewer or maybe since
你一直都没有再看RecyclerView的话
some of the initial releases
你可能会漏掉几个他们目前已经加进去的布局管理器
you may have missed some of the layout
managers they've added
因为,预览版的时候,我们手里的RecyclerView
because during the preview really all we
所提供的基本功能就跟ListView差不多
had was some basic functionality that
was very similar to ListView and they
但是到正式发布的时候,很多新功能都已经被加进去了.
add it quite a bit by the time they got
to release
接下来,我来快速梳理一遍,framework提供了些什么
let's just quickly go through what the
framework gives us the first
首先,是大家都很熟悉的
option which will.familiar to
probably most of you
LinearLayoutManager.
is the linear layout manager so the
LinearLayout manager
你基本可以把它当成ListView的替代品
is essentially the ListView replacement
if you well
尽管它还有些其他的特性,但是基本上它是
I it's got some additional features in
it but is it is a
一个列表项均分的单一列表.LinearLayoutManager有个
uniform single list of items.one of the
neat features
ListView没有的特性.那就是对方向参数的可选性
of linear layout manager that we
didn't have in listview is the optional
那就是对方向参数的可选性
orientation setup
因此LinearLayoutManager允许RecyclerView创建
so LinearLayout Manager allows recycler
view to create a list of items that
可滚动的列表
scrolls
不管是垂直的还是水平的.很明显,我们之前
either vertically or horizontally which
is a new feature that we obviously
是没有这个特性的.
didn't have before
你只需要在LinearLayoutManager实例化的时候
and this is controlled during the
instantiation of the LinearLayout
指定水平或者垂直的方向参数即可
manager just by giving it that vertical
or horizontal orientation qualifier
there
这里最后一个boolean型的参数,代表是你是否要逆序进行
OK. the boolean parameter that at the end
that allows you to also reverse the
布局
layout
通常,大家都是把它设为false
so the traditional by setting it to
false would
那么列表项显示的顺序跟适配器中getView()顺序是一致的
order the items as they viewed in the
adapter so
从位置0开始,由高到低依次依序显示列表项
adapter item position $0 upfront down to
the end
如果你把这个参数设成true,那么就成逆序了.
if you set this parameter to true it
will reverse that and have the
列表中最后一项会先显示.因此,从前ListView的这种特性
end of the adapter show first in the
list okay so they have that feature in
在LinearLayoutManager中也存在
there as well
接下来,framework提供给我们的是GridLayoutManager
the next one that we have appears the
grid layout manager
这个布局管理器在L预览版中是没有的,但是其功能性
so this is...this one was not in the
preview but functionality have it is
我们却不陌生.因为我们都知道GridView
still pretty intuitive to most of us because
we've either seen or used gridview
before
当然,这里的布局管理器更加灵活一点.它的特点是,
at a little bit more flexible than that
but the idea here is that
大体上,我们仍有着均分的网格布局列表项集合
we're still having this uniform
collection of items
但是这些列表项,除了一个挨着一个的布局之外,还能够
but these items can now be stacked up
uh you know, either side by side on
top of each other
uh, just like with linear layout manager
grid layout manager does support
orientation changes so we can do a
vertical scrolling list
like the traditional grid view or we can
flip that into a horizontally scrolling
grid
instead now the the number that you see
in this
declaration here is that the the grid
layout manager supports
controlling how many what they call
spans are associated with that
particular item
now the reason they call them spans
instead of rows or columns is because
the fact that you can do it
either direction saucepan just simply
defines
how many items you can stack up so in a
vertical grid the spans are the columns
in a horizontal grid the span to be the
Rose
K but they're still defined in such a
way that their uniform so
for instance in this case I have two
spans defined so
they will evenly be spaced on both sides
there's not really a mechanism to define
you know sort of a 1/3 2/3 with the
spans
you're necessarily at this level paper
they did at a
fairly interesting feature though that
allows you to change the uniformity
in in some basic ways using something
called a span size lookup
so in the example that I have here the
grid layout manager still has
two spans defined but using this custom
implementation have
a span size lookup we can define at
runtime for
each individual position how many spans
should each item take up and this is a
very simple algorithm basically says
every third item should take two spans
and all the other should take just the
default 1
and this gives us the implementation
that we see up here
where every other row is essentially
laid out
all the way across but the grids
interspersed in between
so you can create some shifting elements
here
but this is always defined in terms of
the number of spans available
so this isn't like a an explicit pics 0
width or anything like that you define
ahead a time how many spans are
available
in this layout and then you can use the
lookup to basically tell it how many of
those you get the government sells in a
table
this specific item should take up at I
it one of the important things to
realize with grid layout though is that
the
whatever orientation it's in the item
height:
or for towards on all the item with
still needs to be uniform for
each element block so for instance in
this example
all the items in the same row have to be
the same height
and the the row height itself will
essentially adjust to whatever the
tallest item is
so if I had one item in the middle the
other two that was much taller
there would be a gap underneath the two
items on either side
they don't slide up to sort of fill in
the gaps or anything like that
for that
we have the staggered grid layout
manager
so the staggered grid layout manager
build on that pattern
and operates and is constructed in a
very similar way to grid layout manager
but in this case we have the opportunity
to define
different size item views and the
staggered grid layout manager will
simply lay them out
as best it knows how underneath each
other filling in those individual gaps
K the firm in implementation perspective
creating one is again no different then
working with the other two ended
also supports horizontal and vertical
orientation
now
wanna the one other things to notice
about each of these that I've shown you
so far is that well they support
different orientations have scrolling
both these implementations only supports
growing in a single axis
at any given time what what I need to do
if I wanted to create a recycler view
implementation or say like a simple grid
that I want to be able to actually
scroll in two directions
can I do that well the answer is yes I'm
really not gonna give you anything to do
that
in that case we have to look at me but
perhaps building our own
so what I've done and I'll show you the
egg
where you can look at the example at the
end to the talk here
is as sort of a case study for what what
we're talking about here
I went through and decided I'm gonna
create at
two-dimensional scrolling layout this
just a simple uniform grid
K so the great is going to be laid out
the positions would basically be the way
you see them up there whether
they order themselves left to right the
grid with is fixed
so the number of columns as wrap around
to the next and I'll just lined
themselves up
like if I was looking at maybe a TV
schedule or sports scores in a greater
something like that
then the user could simply pan and
scroll around
this content visually in whatever
orientation they wanted
okay and the question essentially I pose
to myself was
can I build this with recycler view and
come out saying on the other side
I'll let you decide when I'm done
whether or not that actually worked okay
before I talk about the mechanisms have
what you need to do to build this
about let's discuss a little bit about
the internals
for psych love you so that you can get
some idea of
how these pieces that you may see in the
documentation actually fit together
so the first element but i wanna talk
about in the
the core a utility if you will that
recycler view
gives you is this instance for this
concept a recycler
this is really the workhorse love
building a custom layout the recycler
is a utility given to you by a recycler
view
that does all love the work necessary
for
obtaining views cashing views your
basically doing all the recycling
functionality that you need
to be able to quickly get new views for
new data and toss away views you don't
need anymore
K so when you're building a layout
manager your interaction is almost
exclusively
with the recycler there you know when
when you need a new view
with to the next position the user a
scrolling interview or something like
that you obtain that view from the
recycler
by giving it the position value that you
want so this is the next position I need
please give me the view that has all the
data already bound associated with it
and similarly when you're done with a
view but say it scrolls of screen and
you don't need it anymore
you would toss that back to the recycler
so that it can
keep access to that around and rebind it
in some other data later and headed back
to another point
okay so all that functionality is bound
inside the recycler in the recyclers job
is to talk to the adapter so the adapter
were all your data comes from where you
you creep you holders and bind all the
data that
is iraq there's a direct interaction
between the recycler in the adapter to
get all that information
the key point to remember here is your
layout manager should never
ever ever touch the adapter
that is the recyclers job if you have
are building a layout manager that
somehow is trying to get state
information or some other data directly
from the adapter
that pattern is broken instead the view
holders
that are basically forced down your
throat by the recycler view API
those are great places to hold that
state because the adapter
her has access to the view holder and so
does the layout manager
and recycler view does this internally
are you all the information that that
view knows about its current position
whether it's are changing weather is
being added removed all the things that
recycler view uses for these fancy
transition animations
that state is all held on the beholder
and you can extend that the holder which
your obviously supposed to when you
build your own adapter so if you wanna
stuff more state in there for each
individual view
that's the right way to do that and then
that will transport along with the views
as they move into the layout manager and
and so on and so forth
so always touch the recycler never touch
the adapter
alright so let's look a little bit
deeper into the recycler itself so I
mention that the recycler
is a it's a caching mechanism above all
else
so the recycler is wary you need to get
new views
and you need to toss away your old views
but it turns out that they actually have
a two-level mechanism inside
to make this work the recycler has this
concept of what they call the scrap heap
and then underneath that is this idea of
the recycle poor
now the the difference between them is
fairly nuanced and in a lotta cases it
doesn't
really matter but there are some
optimizations that can be made if you
understand the difference
at the the scrap heap is usually the the
first line of defense or where you would
typically toss abuse
while you're doing layouts and all I'll
explain to you in sort of a technique I
you would
possibly use that in your code but the
scrap heap is a is a very lightweight
place
where views can be tossed and retrieved
back
in a in a very quick fashion often cases
without even having to rebind the data
so it it's a nice place that as a layout
manager
you can toss a buncha views that you
know you're going to reuse again
they're still on screen but maybe you
need to ship them around or something
like that and rather than them having to
go back to the adapter to rebind data
and bring them back to you
I you can just quickly get them back
from the scrap heap
and lay them out again it's a typically
I'll toss things in the scrap heap
first the recycle pool is more commonly
used for views you are certain you don't
need anymore
or so for instance after you've run a
layout maybe you have a handful %uh
views that have scrolled off screen and
you didn't
you didn't need these and you know that
you can toss those into the recycle poor
the recycle pool is still a quick way
over allowing you to get data back
but it tosses away some of the
additional meta-data
basically recycles the view holder and
keeps the viewer around so
even though it can quickly Rehbein data
from the adapter its a little bit more
expensive if you're constantly doing
that for every single view
so typically you would wanna throw views
you know you don't need and recycle into
the recycle poor
toss everything else in this crappy K
and I'll show you a technique that kinda
allows you to do this
on on two different levels the other
concepts that
where illustrating here is the
difference between a detachment and a
removal
I it in the method that I've got appear
that they look like they're bound
together but you can actually do all
these operations separately you can
attach and detach
remove scrap you can do those things
individually these are just convenience
functions
I that syntax is a little stinky in my
opinion because
detaches really I it's a mechanism
similar to scrapping
that allows you to toss a few away
temporarily
that you know you're going to reuse in
the same way out pass
so the while the name is detach
a detached view is not technically
removed from its parent
which is the recycler view it's actually
still added to that view
the layout managers allowed to
manipulate it a little bit so it's much
more lightweight
I but it is still attached to the parent
view
remove view is very similar to you a
view removal you would have little
gonna be a group or anything like that
where it is actually detached from its
parent so it's
its little bit difficult cuz remove
actually detach and attach does not
but you can really think of it as
detaches the lightweight and remove is
the heavyweight
so typically in most cases you do these
things together
so the method on a recycler for detach
in scrap
I is where you would you would use that
to toss to use a way that you
might use again and remove and recycle
is the one you would use to toss use a
way that the next time you need it it's
probably gonna be for different
different use case very different bind
okay couple other
tips just to know when you're building a
layout manager I
layout manager as the name implies is
responsible for measuring and laying out
every view in the recycler view
very similar to the responsibility that
a container view group has for all is
child abuse
I however recycler puke provides this
additional feature to developers call
decorations reviews decorations before
okay pretty good group they allow you to
provide
additional drawing or additional margins
or sizing requirements
on individual items so for instance with
an item decoration
I can define not in the item view itself
but in a declaration that
all of my items should have a margin
around them and it just
recycler view applies that for me I
don't have to do anything with it
and that's true in a way outside as well
I don't have to necessarily know that
when I lay something out
it has a margin and I've in said it the
API handles that part for you
but it only handles that part if you lay
them out appropriately using
a different set of methods and you might
be familiar with if you've done custom
you work in the past
so similarly all the information about
the view
is technically wrong if you ask the view
itself
if I asked the view for its information
like it left right top bottom
those are incorrect because they don't
account for the decoration
instead there are decorated left right
top bottom
that will give you the appropriate value
might need while you're laying out other
views
so for instance if I'm laying out a
bunch abuse in a linear fashion
I would use the decorated top and bottom
values to know where the previous view
was so I can lay out the next one in
front of it or something like that K
similarly we have method like that for
sizing
to the decorated heighten with will
account for those margins as well
and as I mentioned when you're laying
out your views
you need to make sure to use the layout
and measure method on the manager
not calling measure in layout directly
on the child abuse
okay this will if you don't do these
things
and you have an implementation that
doesn't use decoration
it'll look like it's working but as soon
as someone brings in an adapter that has
a decoration
catch to it all your layout will be
confused anymore know why
so as long as you stick to using these
methods in your way out all the time
it'll just work regardless of whether
somebody decorated their content on
art
so the next piece that I wanna talk to
you
about is a concept that I call the Phil
technique
this is how the framework typically does
read view recycling they did it this way
in listview they do it this way in their
core
a layout managers as well on
this is a a function that hopefully will
help simplify the concept love
how you run a layout and how use or to
build a layout manager at all centrally
focused around this concept called the
Phil the Phil is really just a layout
operation but its all encapsulated into
this functionality that is able to check
for the current state
an account for differences in that sort
of thing so typically what she'll have
when you're using this technique is a
single method that you write
there's no fill gap or fill axe method
that lives in recycler view
you would create an internal method that
we just by convention would call Phil
that does these things that I've listed
here so it's going to be responsible for
determining based on the current layout
what is the first
visible position you can see you know it
the
based on how far down the list is
scrolled
the first visible view doesn't
necessarily mean
the first visible position I but YouTube
basically the idea is to enumerate all
those individual views
and figure out based on the views I have
what's the first position I can see
as a position 0 as a position 5 whatever
the case may be
and you'll typically wanna look at that
view and also determine its offset
is the view shifted in any way as it
shifted uppers it shifted down
and as part of that placement to that
view
do I have a gap you know has have the
views
shifted because the user input user
scroll the operation
to the point where I've got some extra
space at the top that I need to fill
with another view
I that's kinda where the term comes from
if I don't
are you know and maybe it shifted the
other way maybe I have a gap at the
bottom
and I need to fill something
so basically it's discovering what's
first finding gaps
where where ever which edger whichever
corner they may live then
and then scrapped everything this is the
part that will save you a bunch of
headache
rather than trying to determine your
current state figure out whether based
on it that shifted this way do this if
it shifted that way do that just get
your current state information about
first visible position and where it
is offset located toss everything in
this crap in
K then from there
take that initial information up the
first viewing the first location
and run a layup pass just whatever logic
%uh
you need to say from this position until
I run out of space
grab views from the recycler and lay
them out and then in that case it
doesn't matter what's first her how far
it is
you always just fill the space with
all the end you all the views that you
need depending on no matter what state
you're currently in
now depending on where your gaps are you
might have to make some adjustments
so for instance if you shift the views
down that gap is above
your first visible position that you
actually to lay out
has popped back one so you may need to
make some adjustment based on the gaps
but once you have that initial
information
and your scrap everything this runaway
out every time
right it's not expensive because a lot
of these views are already laid out so
calling layout again doesn't change any
other properties
I and in it in addition we've toss them
in the scrap heap
so rich retrieving them back from the
recycler is also very cheap
okay so I can do this over and over and
over again and as you know it doesn't
it doesn't necessarily affect the
performance I don't just have to try and
manipulate the spaces that I need and
try to leave all the other views along
you'll get yourself caught in way too
many edge cases if you do that
you can simplify it by just doing the
same process every time
and then this method will be called
whether it's an initial layout
where they were scrolling whether any
state changes on the recycler view which
is gonna go through this exact same
process
alright
questions you would ask yourself about
where my gaps
and the important thing to remember here
is to save his little state as possible
right you want to discover the
information about your view
what's the first visible position what
is it offset don't try to track
that information because that typically
tends to lead to edge cases where you
can track it correctly and then you
your branching a statement all over the
place K use this as a
as stateless a function as you can
possibly do that discovers everything it
needs up front
and then runs the layout appropriately
on each pass
okay
just by way of example this is what Phil
function might look like or are you
might stop one out
so you at the beginning you're going to
have some logic to determine what the
first visible position is depending on
your layout that
your could mean a number of things it's
probably just gonna be something simple
like enumerating overall the child abuse
asking those Child's View holders what
their position are
and may be looking for the lowest value
K that would be true for a linear want
it may not be true depending on what
your
your layout implementation s but
figuring out what that first visible
item years
and if it's necessary what is it offset
is it has it been shifted
so that we need to of your fill a gap or
something like that and then as i
mentioned there are
a helper methods available on the
recycler view
to help you toss away views so the
the two objects that you're going to see
past to you in pretty much every major
framework method
is a recycler instance and something
called the recycler state
and those two things all will work
together
for everything that you need to do
associated with modifying your layout so
in this case
the recycler is passed to this helper
function which is part of the API
that's not something you have to write
just detach in scrap attached views
that says tossed every view that I has
currently attached to me
Jordans crap K and then from there
you can simply iterate through however
many views you need whether you have
like a fixed window size are you just
want to iterate through views and tell
you
run outta space whatever algorithm you
want to use to do this
iterate through those views and get each
one back
from the recycler so get your
position will tell the recycler this is
the position I wanna lay out
and it will give you the view already
bound to the data that you need to do
that layout with
K and then just like you would in any
other view group you need at it
or attach it measure it and lay it out
K then from there
the final job is determining if there
are any views that were in my layout
that I don't need anymore so when I went
through and I scrapped everything
if if the next step is to lay out just
what I need
there may be views that were left in the
scrap heap
and those are views that I scrolled off
screen or for whatever reason I don't
need anymore
because they didn't make it back into
the layout pass you can ask the recycler
view for its current list of what's in
scrap
and if there is anything left in scrap
at this stage I don't need it
so I can recycle it pack so then this
will just go through in
and take the views out at the scrap heap
and explicitly put them in their cycle
poor
okay and that's a more efficient way of
holding those views when you know
that they're gonna need to be rebound
today to later on that doesn't mean that
if you run outta views and recycle
annually views that are available are in
scrap that
it won't be able to rebind them recycle
Rehbein data from scrap or recycle so it
it's not something you necessarily have
to worry about as to whether it will
make your
you work correctly it's just an
optimization
if you use crap in recycle appropriately
then you have the most optimized for
cycling behavior
in terms of memory management that sort
of thing okay
so what are the advantages from the
example that I
had put forth I've doing S II has to do
with viewing the Seas
my mother for her problems that I doubt
whether when dealing with this is the
sixth grade implementation
was unlike a traditional linear single
scrolling
implementation the view indices aren't
always consistent
you know something like a LinearLayout
or even a grid layout you can typically
rely on the fact that
the first views in the list are the
first visible
and the last views in less than the last
visible and you can rely on a
a fairly consistent mapping between view
indices
and positions you know when you scroll
up you would
typically insert pews at the front and
if as you scroll down you would
appended to the ender vice versa but
that's not necessarily true with this
case you know in this case if the
if the user is looking at some block up
element in the middle of the grid
the view indices might look something
like this: based on the way I played
them out
but you can kinda see that on the left
and the right hand side there
those views our part love the range
from the adapters perspective they just
aren't visible right now
so you can imagine that as a shift the
window across these views
they will be Barack brought in as group
so I would bring in maybe
for call r4 views in the next column
maybe a couple for the New Ro
and accompanied in groups that could be
coming from all four sides
so if I want to rely on any sort
love consistency in the view indices I
need to toss everything away and relay
out and that insures that child 0 is
always at the top left
child whatever is at the bottom right
pay
otherwise I can and I'm not saying you
have to rely on that but
a little trick to help keep your sanity
here is if you can be relatively sure
that the child indices are in the right
order all the time then it it to help
simplify some of that inspection logic
that you may need to do later on for
changes and stuff like that
that's just an advantage abusing that
implementation
and this depending on your functionality
and how you mutate that still method I
showed you
you can use attach and detach manually
to reorder these views so you know if
you're not necessarily scrapping them
but for whatever reason you just want to
reorder them so that the same views have
different indices that are in this order
detach the mall and reattach them in the
right order that will
that will give them the proper view
index from a child perspective insider
the parent parent view
okay so let's talk a little bit about
the steps to build one of these think so
assuming that you have a proper Phil
method put together
one that sorta follows that recipe that
I showed you I
this is sorta how we would put put these
things in place so the first
the first level that I call it have a
working recycler the layout
I'm is just to get the thing working
right so that there's a handful call
back
you need to to override and implement
just to get an actual layout manager
functioning
the first one is on layout children this
is the initial method
they will be called by the framework
anytime a significant layout change
happens to the recycler view
the recycler view will delegate to the
manager that'd
it needs to do a new layout you only out
children this is not called repeatedly
meaning it's not called on every change
but it'll be called for initial layout
will be called if the size are the
recycler view changes if you ever call
request layout on the recycler view this
is what you're gonna see
and again if you have inappropriately
written Phil method all you have to do
in years running whether you have to use
in there already or whether it's empty
doesn't matter you just run your fell
inside a fear and be done
okay but we want to add a little bit
abuser act in there interactivity to
this function as well
I so you have to determine are you have
to report back to route the framework in
recycler view
which axis can this view scroll and
cannot scroll vertically
can scroll horizontally or in my case of
so in most of these cases you would only
return true
from one of these methods but the fix
graydon implementation returns it for
both so that it can scroll both
horizontally and vertically at the same
time
if you don't return trip from these
methods then
the recycler view implementation simply
won't delivery vans back to you
knowing that you're scrolling one
direction the other basically locks
scrolling
in that particular orientation but
the actual implementation of this
growing functionality happens in the
Skrillex by methods so scroll
horizontally or vertically by
these methods will be called repeatedly
very similar to the scroll by method you
would see on a viewer view group
as user interaction is coming in so it
is the responsibility
other the layout manager to handle
moving the views
recycle view doesn't do that for you
okay it just gives you the information
up front to be able to do that
so these methods will be called with the
information that the framework has
determined from the user input
basically they'll give you a delta value
in this is called incrementally
have how far the framework thinks you
should shift your views
and of course in which direction
horizontally or vertically thanks
and then it will be up to you to
actually do
the movement as well as making any
determinations about boundary conditions
rate the
the layout managers responsible for
telling the framework when you hit the
end of the content any need to stop
scrolling
in that particular direction K now that
report is actually done in the terms the
return value
so win whatever value you return from
this function
designates to the framework how far you
actually traveled
and in the framework will make a
determination based on how much how far
it told you to travel
if there's a difference there it assumes
it's had a boundary and it's going to do
things for you like drawing edge close
and other edge effect behavior that you
probably don't wanna see if you're not
all the way at the end yet to be very
careful about how that return value
actually comes up
so this is kind of an example
love what you might see this is a a snap
to version of what's in fixed grid for
scroll horizontally
so you're given a value that they call
in this case Deacs
thats how far they think you should
scroll first thing you have to determine
perhaps based on which direction that's
growing occurs is
can I scroll that far or have I hit a
boundary
and determine how far you're actually
going to shift now the nice thing is
you don't have to iterate over the child
abuse in individually move them
recycler be layout manager provides of
these offset children methods both
horizontal and vertical
that will do the the work I've shifting
all views that are currently attached
so all you have to determine is the
actual difference
and then just passed that into the
method but because recycler view doesn't
really know how your layout looks
once the views have been moved you may
have created a gap so it's up to you
to go back and run another Phil K now in
my implementation and you can look at
the details
in the example and get her but in my
implementation I actually provided
direction keyword back to the Phil just
to help sort of assessed when I needed
to shift my
my positions backwards or forward based
on which way this rowing was going on
that's not really required in the
technique that I'm describing it just
it was helpful for my bi directional
scrolling on
but it it's not really part A its
whatever your algorithm needs
a you know to be able to do that in the
most efficient way
okay and then as I mention the return
value their
has to be the difference up what was
actually scrolled
if you just take this a new dish return
Deacs you'll never end up scrolling
and if you always return 0 never scroll
at all anytime you try to scroll you'll
just get infinity edge close all the
time
okay so you have to be very specific
about when you can and when you can't
move
based on whether or not you've hit a
boundary of your content
okay at a minimum
that's it that's all you really need to
implement to get a working
layout managers something that will lay
views out you can move them around
you know all the things you would expect
from user interaction perspective
other additional features you can add
and probably should add
overtime but thats or to the basics like
even get that far you can at least
determine if your other than works in
your layout functionalities okay and all
that sort of thing I
the next step if you have additional
time is
typically to start reacting to dataset
changes
cannes is really not a whole lot of work
to do here most ovett is built right and
but
there is one additional method here
called on adapter changed
that you can provide some optimizations
insider
you don't have to override this but it
can be helpful this will be triggered
if the recycler view ever is provided
with a completely different
adapter instance so if their call if
they call said adapter again with some
other object in this will be called in
the layout manager
and you can use that for as an
optimization opportunity
to simply clear all the views no notice
I'm not tossing them to the recycler
I just want them removed completely the
assumption here is that
if we're getting a completely new
adapter it's definitely new data
and it's probably going to be in your
view types as well so there's no need
for me to dump everything I have into
the recycler cuz this is going to end up
having a toss those away later anyway
not that we would break if it did that
but we can optimize that out
by saying if the adapter changes just
remove everything
bypass the Recycle don't like two
hundred dollars K
now we all know notified is a change in
an adapter right
if if something has changed in the data
we trigger this method to update the
view
right was that way in listview still
exists in recycler view
at a at a base implementation you don't
have to do anything different here
are notified is a change just triggers a
new layout change
and if your fill a game is set up
appropriately uydess relay out
right the only thing you might want to
persist in this is sorted implementation
dependent is
for a at for an adapter change you might
wanna persist with the current first
position was
so you may want to discover that before
you run your fill but again depending on
how you've written your fill you're
probably already doing that anyway
so they can attempt with the new data to
lay out from the same first visible
position
okay but if you if you toss those away
already or something like that you may
want to track that value
just very briefly until the new layout
comes around or something like that
otherwise you could just lay it out from
the beginning it would still work
the one a caveat to this is that if your
adapter has stable ladies
I recycler view assumes at that point
that it actually has enough data to
train and meet the change
and so calling notified is a change will
trigger an animation sequence
and we'll talk about animations a little
bit later but if you if your adapter
doesn't do that
this will just be a a snap layout
cannibal adjust to the new data
alright well let's say that we happen to
have a little bit more extra time on our
hands we want to get a little bit more
fancy with this functionality
I the next feature that we can add to
our managers targets growing
so the at external API's for allowing
a developer to scroll your layout to a
specific position whether that
immediately
or in some animated fashion again are
not baked and you have to provide some
implementation how that works
so for the scrolled position case which
is a non animated case
it can be pretty simple just like in the
case I mentioned before
you would need to track somehow what the
requested position was
and then just call request layout that
will trigger a new layout which will
trigger on layout children which you can
just do fill
right so if you can start to see how if
you do your
bill right it becomes everything to you
and you don't have to do a whole lot
else to sort of decorate around
K to get a little bit more fancy we have
the smooth scroll to position
and this is where we would want as a
developer we would want the view to
actually
animate into place K now the
the functionality for doing this
requires an implementation of something
called a smooth scroller this is an
abstract class provided by the
by the framework that you can override
and create your own implementation
have essentially what should happen on
an incremental basis
as it animates around your view trying
to find the target
K this interface is actually fairly
complex there's
I'd I can't remember five to 10 methods
that you have to override to make that
happen
I you can certainly do that if you're
not a
if you're not happy with the behavior
that the framework gives you
but there is an implementation called
linear smooth scroller that is provided
a in support package that you can just
text and this does most of the work for
you
by providing a linearly interpolated
animation
on its way to whatever the target
position yes and the only piece of
information you have to provide in this
case
is where is the target position and
that's from a cordon its perspective
so when when this method is called
smooth scroll the position you basically
have to figure out what's the first
visible position I have now
what's the target that they're trying to
get to and then this computation what
they call a vector
on what is the direction that I need to
scroll to get there
is at left is that right is it up is it
down to the diagonal but has to be some
linear value
guy and so you would typically figure
out what's the conceptual distance
between the two
based on you know whatever guess you can
put together
in my case all these are the same size
so I can have a really good guess
because I knew exactly how far would
need to travel
but that may not necessarily be the case
it doesn't have to be the exact distance
it just has to know the direction
and then when your smile scroller is
gonna go through and run an incremental
fashion
they're gonna walk through they're just
going to incrementally animate
and scroll in whatever direction it
needs to get to that position
and it'll scroll can't see if it's been
laid out scroll again
see if it's been laid out its just gonna
hunt and hunt until
the position that it's interested in has
finally come into the layout which is
going to be triggering your scroll
method that you've already written
an innocent as it finds that value then
it will stop scrolling
wanted that fully visible on on the
display at that point then it will just
your and K so you can override the SMA
scroller
set the target position and to start it
and that's really the simplest and
the implementation to animated scrolling
K alright
the last piece if you have a lot extra
time
and maybe some sanity left you can
attempt
to add some animation support now out of
the box
recycler view does support what they
called defile to fault
item animations K where the new features
a recycler view that was not as easy to
implement something like this view was
if you inserted a new item or removed it
or made some changes
animating all that in a nice fancy way
for the user
K the the functionality with all the
core layout managers
is to provide a very basic algorithm for
that out of the box
and have an animation to show you what
that looks like but essentially it just
looks at the views
looks at the change before and after and
then tries to determine based on this
layout in this layout in the two
snapshots
what pews have gone away what use are
new and what you have moved around
and it will fade out the old views fade
in the new views in
simply translate the other ones on
screen okay
and in a lot of cases it does a pretty
good job but you'll see there are some
problems with what you get for free if
you're doing a custom layout because you
may be
animating views off-screen that because
they're no longer there the default
animation just thinks they've
disappeared
so it fades them out incident gracefully
moving them to where they conceptually
were supposed to go
K and so we'll take a look at what you
need to do to Sir provide that so
and recalls that predictive item
animations and if you want to support
that in your layout manager
you just have to tell them to say yes I
support predictive animations return
trip from this method
and this will change your layout
behavior just a little bit
in this case anytime in item changes
triggered
now for an initial layout or anything
like that still gonna be the same
but you
moving item or you insert and item
something like that and that item is
visible
at the moment then the layout process
actually becomes a
to pass layout it calls on layout
children first in what they called the
pre layout state
this is a state where all the views all
the data from the adapter
is massage such that it looks the way it
would have looked
before the change this gives you an
opportunity to run a layout pass
in what they call the pre layout or the
the initial snapshot
K so from from the views on screen
perspective this means you just
run your traditional Phil but you might
need 10
make note if any interviews that were
on-screen were removed
you've got gaps to fill and if you just
let the default animations do their work
they will animate until they can see
that gap in the notice paid the new view
n
but if you wanna make it look like the
view actually slides into place
you have to lay it out during this pass
and you lay it out in the location of
screen where it should come from
K so those are what they call appearing
views
and they give you additional information
on the layout parameters which you can
get from the view holder
for each individual view as to whether
or not this view that you can see
has actually been removed in the next
step it's gone and if that's the case
you say wow I've got
maybe two or three views that were
removed I need to make sure
I add two or three appearing views in
wherever they should be so that the
animation brings them in the way they're
supposed to look
okay you want to take note of how many
removed so that you can use that for the
appearing views
the other thing that you would typically
do during this step
is take some stock up what's currently
in the layout
so that after the fact you can determine
if any are the views
had been that weren't miss explicitly
removed are no longer in the layout
because they shifted
off-screen and if that's the case you
need to lay them out
during the second phase which is the the
regular layout
phase in their off-screen positions K
so during pre layout you have to lay out
those appearing views
and just take note up what the stated
that snapshot its
and then run your fill the way you
normally
a word then that methods gonna be called
again in this case that
is pre layout is gonna be set to false
and this is no different than any other
Phil
now all the adapter positions in all the
values are set the way they are
after the change and you can lay
everything out and then you just have
that final step
saying OK at this point I don't need
this P senator
this piece has gone away I need to lay
it out of screen so that the animation
can slide in the right direction
K let's
a take a look at a quick example here
you can get an idea there so
now you're on layout children might look
a little bit more complicated right
so during pre layout is where you're
going to make that information
check that information about how many
views were actually removed
were there any if there was a view
removed then I need to account for that
by adding some appearing logic so
in in my implementation if you look at
the example I added that to the sill
so the fill his also passed if there are
any additional appearing to use that it
needs to add
and it lays those out in addition to
what it would otherwise be able to see
okay so that's kind of hidden in here
and similarly
we can look after pre layout after we've
at dawn are still for real and we can
check that scrap list again and say was
there anything that was left in scrap
if there was then those are actually
disappearing pews they were removed
or and they you anything like that so we
lay them out again
so you you could run to fill what but
usually easier is just too abstract that
layout logic in call it again for that
specific view
and figure out this is where the view
should be off-screen K
alright to discreetly show you what that
difference looks like
presso with default item animations on
the example that I had
this is kind of what you get and you can
you can see how it's not exactly what we
were looking for. so in this case the
red byu
is the one we're going to remove and the
green views are the ones that should
shift location but they don't quite do
what they're supposed to
right so when we remove this view what
happens is that
all the views on the left also fade out
and then they fade in in their new
locations
and that's because it does the recycler
view doesn't know any better
he just knows that after pre layout they
weren't there anymore
and then it when I scroll over to see
where they actually are
they'll show up there in the new layout
K by adding proper predictive animation
support I can modify that behavior and
again this is the way the example
actually works if you go
run it I can modify their behaviors that
those green views
slide off-screen to where they're
supposed to go
into that direction que nos from the
user screen I'll probably just slight
off-screen unless it is a large enough
display for the next we see the whole
thing
but in that case they actually
that you get the benefit love the user
seeing where they should go
so that when they scroll over they're
actually there right it's that idea of
teaching the user how things are
supposed to go by animating them to the
proper locations
if they just of a doubt they might think
they remove them all which is not
correct
K so that's the idea behind implementing
predictive item animations to give you
some better intro
okay so
couple more pieces of information to
wrap up here so
the example that I've been discussing
here I is on my get her page
that application also has a few other
basic samples in it for using the grid
layout managers and things like that but
has the full source code for that fixed
grid implementations you can dive into
all that
carry details if you're interested I
also went through a series a fairly
detailed blog posts as I was building
that thing
so if you wanna get a sense for how much
carry actually tore out while doing this
you can go through and read that
specifically if you're doing anything
similar to what I did with that
that sort of disconnected range where
the grid and what you're seeing
is actually just a subset up the overall
layout but the views that are in between
are actually in the middle of the range
which you wouldn't typically have with
the linear you might want to read the
last
blog post that I call the redox where I
actually discuss some other bugs and
issues with the layout manager API that
actually makes that implementation much
more difficult than it should be
and some other things you have to do to
work around that if you're doing a much
more simpler implementation that either
single accessor doesn't have that
disconnection problem
then you won't have any issues like that
but it might be an interesting read
and then the STK also has some pretty
good documentation and is getting you
started
with recycler view their okay
so looking at the time I don't know that
we have
any time for questions couple okay
it will take a couple questions and then
if there anymore or can walk a state so
I saw him first up
me
we remember they don't affect the
decorators
clip their for
truth
that's correct the other
the the information because you
depending on how you implement the
actual decorator
if you're using that information have
basically what's the height or the with
the child to know where to draw those
lines
that information is not updated
incrementally
I'm so it's only gonna be updated when
its in its initial state
and then after the change it should give
you the new information so
you might see it jump into words proper
position as but it won't transition like
that because that information is not
are you if I called again get decorated
height on that view
on each of those instances it's not
going to change until the
the values actually its new state cuz
from a from that perspective
the height itself is not incremental it
has its initial state and its final
state joining the changes the drawing
so you have to you have to somehow
listen for that event
and try to trigger it manually which you
can do I
the layout manager does have a handful
methods for on item removed added answer
to that sort of thing
that can signal you win that event is
occurring
so that you can strike a match it as
best you can with your animation
but otherwise that ya unfortunately it
doesn't give you that feedback directly
in the decorator
yes obsolete
I'll keeps Las the
here that
she eighty
aim to be fully Steelers if you can
manage it in my
so I'll give you an example from the way
I built it so the initial implementation
iro
I am I track very heavily things like
the first visible position
and that position offset and I kept that
state around
all the time and win when we started
doing dataset changes where we went from
like a really large grid to really small
greater something like that a
trying to assume that that value was
even valid anymore
lead to a long list if statements well
if I shifted
all the way down and leadership back but
if I shifted from here I need to do this
and if I had just basically run a new
Phil we're at that point I say okay
based on what I've got
what am I supposed to be able to see
it would have been a much simpler flow
so I mean as far as good state to track
that mean the only thing that I would
recommend in a basic implementation you
track
is any target positions your you're
moving towards
so if you're doing a linear scroll or if
you doing scroll to position and you're
going to get a new layout past you kinda
have to track
where you wanna go cuz that's not passed
around for you
but in general anything about the
current state of the layout
if you can get away with it and in most
cases I think you should be able to
you shouldn't have to track anything and
if you do and as per item
stick in the roller a
Missy former question I think we have
time for yes customs
whose yes crews you
runs him
oh you mean like for fling behavior
it's not really exposed so if you were
to do it you would have to override the
recycler view itself as well
and kinda modify the API a little bit so
I am really look at doing it
it would be possible but its it's not
given to you that behavior is really
define internally the only when you're
giving is the
is the animation part of that that's not
user directed
core alright well thanks for your time
guys if you have any other questions all
step after the site here we can address
on that